<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM21Q3EV">
<servcat id="38">
<name>HEATER &amp; AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM</name>
<section id="1002K_S000R" variety="S000R">
<name>AIR CONDITIONING</name>
<ttl id="1002K_S000R_7AVQ5_T00A7" variety="T00A7">
<name>AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM (for Automatic Air Conditioning System)</name>
<para id="RM000002LIL02LX" category="L" type-id="3001A" name-id="AC33G-55" from="201202">
<name>PRECAUTION</name>
<subpara id="RM000002LIL02LX_z0" proc-id="RM21Q0EV__00004PL00000">
<content5 releasenbr="1">
<step1>
<ptxt>IF ANY OF FOLLOWING CONDITIONS ARE MET, KEEP ENGINE IDLING (ENGINE SPEED AT LESS THAN 2000 RPM) WITH AIR CONDITIONING SWITCH ON FOR AT LEAST 2 MINUTES</ptxt>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Refrigerant gas has been refilled or parts of the air conditioning system have been replaced.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>The engine has not been started for a long time.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<atten3>
<ptxt>If the engine speed is more than 2000 rpm, the cooler compressor assembly may be damaged.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>DO NOT HANDLE REFRIGERANT IN AN ENCLOSED AREA OR NEAR AN OPEN FLAME</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="AC02810E13" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<table>
<title>Text in Illustration</title>
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colname="COL1" colwidth="0.41in"/>
<colspec colname="COL2" colwidth="3.72in"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>*1</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle">
<ptxt>Charging Cylinder</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>ALWAYS WEAR EYE PROTECTION</ptxt>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>BE CAREFUL NOT TO GET LIQUID REFRIGERANT IN YOUR EYES OR ON YOUR SKIN</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="AC02811" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<ptxt>If liquid refrigerant gets in your eyes or on your skin:</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Wash the area with lots of cold water.</ptxt>
<atten2>
<ptxt>Do not rub your eyes or skin.</ptxt>
</atten2>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Apply clean petroleum jelly to the skin.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Go immediately to a hospital or see a physician for professional treatment.</ptxt>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>NEVER HEAT CONTAINER OR EXPOSE IT TO OPEN FLAME</ptxt>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>BE CAREFUL NOT TO DROP CONTAINER OR APPLY PHYSICAL SHOCKS TO IT</ptxt>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>DO NOT OPERATE COMPRESSOR WITH INSUFFICIENT REFRIGERANT IN REFRIGERANT SYSTEM</ptxt>
<ptxt>If there is not enough refrigerant in the refrigerant system, oil lubrication will be insufficient and compressor burnout may occur. Necessary care should be taken to avoid this.</ptxt>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>DO NOT OPEN HIGH PRESSURE MANIFOLD VALVE WHILE COMPRESSOR IS OPERATING</ptxt>
<ptxt>Open and close only the low pressure valve. Opening and closing the high pressure valve could cause the charging cylinder to rupture.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="N011084E19" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<table>
<title>Text in Illustration</title>
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colname="COL1" colwidth="0.41in"/>
<colspec colname="COL2" colwidth="3.72in"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>*a</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle">
<ptxt>Incorrect</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>*b</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle">
<ptxt>Correct</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>BE CAREFUL NOT TO OVERCHARGE SYSTEM WITH REFRIGERANT</ptxt>
<ptxt>If the refrigerant is overcharged, it causes problems such as insufficient cooling, poor fuel economy and engine overheating.</ptxt>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>DO NOT OPERATE ENGINE AND COOLER COMPRESSOR ASSEMBLY WITHOUT REFRIGERANT</ptxt>
<atten3>
<ptxt>This may damage the inside of the cooler compressor assembly.</ptxt>
</atten3>
</step1>
</content5>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>