<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM21Q3EV">
<servcat id="36">
<name>BRAKE</name>
<section id="1000N_S000N" variety="S000N">
<name>BRAKE</name>
<ttl id="1000N_S000N_7A80H_T004V" variety="T004V">
<name>BRAKE SYSTEM</name>
<para id="RM0000010KZ00YX" category="L" type-id="3001A" name-id="BR06C-18" from="201202">
<name>PRECAUTION</name>
<subpara id="RM0000010KZ00YX_z0" proc-id="RM21Q0EV__00001P000000">
<content5 releasenbr="1">
<atten3>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Take extra care to replace each part properly. Improper installation or repair could affect the performance of the brake system and cause a driving hazard.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>It is very important to keep the brake system parts and the work area clean when repairing the brake system.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>If the vehicle is equipped with a mobile communication system, refer to the Precautions in the INTRODUCTION section (See page <xref label="Seep01" href="RM000000UYX0D4X"/>).</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Care must be taken when using magnets as they could affect the performance of the speed sensors.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Since the brake line is one of the critical safety related parts, be sure to disassemble the components if a brake fluid leak is found. If any abnormality is found, replace the component with a new one.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>When removing brake components, cover the brake tube connections to prevent foreign matter such as dust or dirt from entering the tubes.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Do not damage or deform the brake tubes when removing or installing them.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>When installing a brake tube grommet to the body, ensure that the brake tube passes through the center of the grommet.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>When installing a brake tube or flexible hose, ensure that they will not be twisted or bent.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>If the cap of the flexible hose does not match the groove on the bracket, twist the hose slightly to insert it.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Do not reuse a clip removed from a flexible hose.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Flexible hoses must be free from absorber oil, grease, etc.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>When installing a brake tube to a plastic clamp, ensure that the brake tube is not loose or being pinched.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Do not reuse a clip or plastic clamp removed from a flexible hose.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>After installing a brake tube and flexible hose, ensure that they do not interfere with any other components.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Do not allow brake fluid to adhere to any painted surface such as the vehicle body. If brake fluid leaks onto any painted surface, immediately wash it off.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Follow these procedures when disconnecting and connecting the flexible hose and brake tube.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="G033536E21" width="2.775699831in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
</item>
<list2 type="ordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Remove the clip.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Hold the flexible hose with a wrench and disconnect the brake tube with a union nut wrench without deforming the tube.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Connect the brake tube with a union nut wrench without deforming the tube.</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Follow these procedures when connecting the brake tube and 2-way.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="G033443" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</item>
<list2 type="ordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Support the 2-way to prevent deformation to the brake tube and connect the brake tube to the 2-way with a union nut wrench.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Support the 2-way to prevent deformation to the brake tube and install the bolt to fix the 2-way to the body.</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
</atten3>
</content5>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>