<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM21Q3EV">
<servcat id="39">
<name>RESTRAINTS</name>
<section id="1000Y_S000S" variety="S000S">
<name>SUPPLEMENTAL RESTRAINT SYSTEM</name>
<ttl id="1000Y_S000S_7A81B_T005P" variety="T005P">
<name>AIRBAG SYSTEM</name>
<para id="RM000000YVR01DX" category="L" type-id="3001A" name-id="RS0GP-40" from="201303">
<name>PRECAUTION</name>
<subpara id="RM000000YVR01DX_z0" proc-id="RM21Q0EV__000020M00001">
<content5 releasenbr="1">
<atten2>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>The vehicle is equipped with a Supplemental Restraint System (SRS), which consists of a steering pad, instrument panel passenger airbag assembly, front seat outer belt, center airbag sensor and front airbag sensor. Failure to carry out service procedures in the correct sequence could cause SRS parts to unexpectedly deploy and possibly lead to serious injuries. Furthermore, if a mistake is made when servicing SRS parts, they may fail to operate when required. Before performing servicing (including installation/removal, inspection and replacement of parts), be sure to read the following precautions.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Before starting work, wait at least 90 seconds after the ignition switch is turned off and after the cable of the negative (-) battery terminal is disconnected. (SRS parts are equipped with a backup power source. If work is started within 90 seconds of turning the ignition switch off and disconnecting the cable from the negative (-) battery terminal, SRS parts may deploy.)</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Do not expose SRS parts directly to hot air or flames.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten2>
<atten3>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Malfunction symptoms of SRS parts are difficult to confirm. DTCs are the most important source of information when troubleshooting. During troubleshooting, always confirm DTCs before disconnecting the cable from the negative (-) battery terminal.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>For minor collisions where SRS parts do not deploy, always inspect the SRS parts.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Before repair work, remove airbag sensors as necessary if any kind of impact is likely to occur to an airbag sensor during the operation.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Never use SRS parts from another vehicle. When replacing SRS parts, replace them with new ones.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Never disassemble or attempt to repair SRS parts.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>If an SRS part has been dropped, or if there are any cracks, dents or other defects in the case, bracket or connector, replace the SRS part with a new one.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Use an ohmmeter/voltmeter with high impedance (10 kΩ/V minimum) for troubleshooting the electrical circuits.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Information labels are attached to the periphery of SRS parts. Follow the cautions and instructions on the labels.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>After work on SRS parts is completed, perform the SRS warning light check (See page <xref label="Seep01" href="RM000000YVX019X"/>).</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>If the vehicle is equipped with a mobile communication system, refer to the precautions in the INTRODUCTION section (See page <xref label="Seep02" href="RM000001126016X"/>).</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>After turning the ignition switch off, waiting time may be required before disconnecting the cable from the battery terminal. Therefore, make sure to read the disconnecting the cable from the battery terminal notice before proceeding with work (See page <xref label="Seep03" href="RM000000UYX0D4X"/>).</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>When disconnecting the cable from the negative (-) battery terminal, initialize the following system(s) after the cable is reconnected (See page <xref label="Seep04" href="RM000001126016X"/>).</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten3>
<step1>
<ptxt>HANDLING PRECAUTIONS FOR AIRBAG SENSOR</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>In this section, the center airbag sensor, front airbag sensor LH, and front airbag sensor RH are collectively referred to as the airbag sensors.</ptxt>
</atten4>
<step2>
<ptxt>Before replacement of the airbag sensor, wait at least 90 seconds after disconnecting the cable from the negative (-) battery terminal.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>When connecting or disconnecting an airbag sensor connector, ensure that all of the sensors are installed in the vehicle.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Do not use the airbag sensors if they have been dropped.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Do not disassemble the airbag sensors.</ptxt>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>INSPECTION PROCEDURE FOR VEHICLE INVOLVED IN ACCIDENT</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>When the airbag has not deployed, confirm the DTC by checking the SRS warning light. If there is any malfunction in the SRS, perform troubleshooting.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>When any of the airbags have deployed, replace the related airbag sensor and inspect its normal operation.</ptxt>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>SRS CONNECTORS</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>SRS connectors are located as shown in the following illustration.</ptxt>
</atten4>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="C247556E06" width="7.106578999in" height="5.787629434in"/>
</figure>
<table pgwide="1">
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colname="COL2" colwidth="3.54in"/>
<colspec colname="COL3" colwidth="3.54in"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Connector Type</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<ptxt>Application</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Terminal Twin-lock Mechanism</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<ptxt>Connectors 2, 4, 5, 6, 7</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Activation Prevention Mechanism</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<ptxt>Connectors 2, 8, 10, 12</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Half Connection Prevention Mechanism</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<ptxt>Connectors 4, 6, 7</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<ptxt>Connector Lock Mechanism</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry>
<ptxt>Connector 9, 11</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<step2>
<ptxt>All connectors in the SRS are yellow (to distinguish them from other connectors). Some connectors have special functions and are specially designed for the SRS. These connectors use durable gold-plated terminals, and are located as shown above to ensure high reliability.</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>Terminal twin-lock mechanism:</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="Z005953E02" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<list1 type="nonmark">
<item>
<ptxt>Each connector has a two-piece component consisting of a housing and spacer. This design enables the terminal to be locked securely by 2 locking devices (the retainer and lance) to prevent terminals from becoming unseated.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Activation prevention mechanism:</ptxt>
<list1 type="nonmark">
<item>
<ptxt>Each connector contains a short spring plate. When the connector is disconnected, the short spring plate automatically connects the positive (+) terminal and negative (-) terminal of the squib.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="R010587E07" width="7.106578999in" height="4.7836529in"/>
</figure>
</item>
</list1>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Half connection prevention mechanism:</ptxt>
<list1 type="nonmark">
<item>
<ptxt>If the connector is not completely connected, the connector is disconnected by the spring. </ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="H040180E02" width="7.106578999in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</item>
</list1>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Connector lock mechanism:</ptxt>
<list1 type="nonmark">
<item>
<ptxt>Locking the connector lock button connects the connector securely.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="H040181E10" width="7.106578999in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</item>
</list1>
</step3>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>DEPLOYMENT CONDITION</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>When the vehicle is in a collision and the shock is greater than the specified value, the SRS is activated automatically. The safing sensor and deceleration sensor are built into the center airbag sensor. The safing sensor is designed to be turned on at a smaller deceleration rate than the deceleration sensor. The deceleration sensor determines whether or not SRS deployment is necessary based on signals from the front airbag sensor. Current flows to the squibs to deploy the SRS when the conditions shown in the illustration below are met.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B110255E13" width="7.106578999in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>DISCONNECTION OF CONNECTOR FOR STEERING PAD, INSTRUMENT PANEL PASSENGER AIRBAG ASSEMBLY AND FRONT SEAT OUTER BELT ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Release the lock button of the connector using a screwdriver.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Insert the screwdriver tip between the connector and base, and then raise the connector. </ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="H042906E22" width="7.106578999in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>CONNECTION OF CONNECTOR FOR STEERING PAD, INSTRUMENT PANEL PASSENGER AIRBAG ASSEMBLY AND FRONT SEAT OUTER BELT ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Connect the connector.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Push the lever in to connect the holder (with connectors). Check that it locks and that a "click" sound is heard.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="H043151E23" width="7.106578999in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>DISCONNECTION OF CONNECTOR FOR CENTER AIRBAG SENSOR</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Pull the lever by pushing the part labeled A and disconnect the holder (with connectors).</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B109666E04" width="7.106578999in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
<atten4>
<ptxt>If replacement of the holder is necessary, proceed to the next step.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Replace the holder.</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>Using a screwdriver, unlock the retainer.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B149684E01" width="7.106578999in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Release the lance fittings and remove the connectors from the holder.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B109668E03" width="7.106578999in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Install the connectors to a new holder. Check that they lock and that a "click" sound is heard.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="B109670E03" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Lock the retainer.</ptxt>
</step3>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>CONNECTION OF CONNECTOR FOR CENTER AIRBAG SENSOR</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Firmly insert the holder (with connectors) until it cannot be pushed any further.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>The holder slides when connected. Be sure not to hold the lever while connecting, as it may result in an insecure fit.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Push the lever in to connect the holder (with connectors). Check that it locks and that a "click" sound is heard.</ptxt>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>DISCONNECTION OF CONNECTOR FOR INSTRUMENT PANEL PASSENGER AIRBAG ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Place a finger on the slider.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Slide the slider to release the lock.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Disconnect the connector.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="H001586E10" width="7.106578999in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>CONNECTION OF CONNECTOR FOR INSTRUMENT PANEL PASSENGER AIRBAG ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Connect the connector as shown in the illustration. Check that it locks and that a "click" sound is heard.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>Do not touch the slider while it is moving.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="H043731E09" width="7.106578999in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</atten4>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>DISCONNECTION OF CONNECTOR FOR FRONT AIRBAG SENSOR (LH AND RH)</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="H002763E18" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<step2>
<ptxt>Hold the sides of the outer connector locking sleeve and slide it as shown in the illustration to release the connector lock.</ptxt>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Disconnect the connector.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>Be sure to hold both sides of the sleeve. Holding the top and bottom will make disconnection difficult. </ptxt>
</atten4>
</step2>
</step1>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="H002764E02" width="7.106578999in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<step1>
<ptxt>CONNECTION OF CONNECTOR FOR FRONT AIRBAG SENSOR (LH AND RH)</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Connect the connector as shown in the illustration. Check that it locks and that a "click" sound is heard.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>Do not hold the sleeve while it is moving.</ptxt>
</atten4>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="H046058E09" width="7.106578999in" height="2.775699831in"/>
</figure>
</step2>
</step1>
</content5>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>