<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM21Q3EV">
<servcat id="33">
<name>TRANSMISSION</name>
<section id="1000Q_S000E" variety="S000E">
<name>A45DE AUTOMATIC TRANSMISSION</name>
<ttl id="1000Q_S000E_7A7ZH_T003V" variety="T003V">
<name>AUTOMATIC TRANSMISSION SYSTEM</name>
<para id="RM000000U9U0C6X" category="L" type-id="3001A" name-id="AT0044-131" from="201202">
<name>PRECAUTION</name>
<subpara id="RM000000U9U0C6X_z0" proc-id="RM21Q0EV__000016M00000">
<content5 releasenbr="1">
<atten2>
<ptxt>When using compressed air, always aim away from yourself to prevent Automatic Transmission Fluid (ATF) or kerosene from spraying on your face.</ptxt>
</atten2>
<atten3>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>The automatic transmission is composed of precision-made parts, necessitating careful inspection before reassembly because even a small nick could cause fluid leakage or affect performance.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>The procedures are organized so that you work on only one component group at a time. This will help avoid confusion with similar-looking parts of different sub-assemblies being on your workbench at the same time.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>The component groups are inspected and repaired from the converter housing side.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Whenever possible, complete the inspection, repair and reassembly before proceeding to the next component group. If a defect is found in a certain component group during reassembly, inspect and repair this group immediately. If a component group cannot be assembled because parts are being ordered, be sure to keep all parts of the group in a separate container while proceeding with disassembly, inspection, repair and reassembly of other component groups.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Use of Toyota Genuine ATF Type T-IV is recommended.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>All disassembled parts should be washed clean, and compressed air should be blown through any fluid passages and holes.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Dry all parts with compressed air. Never use cloth.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>The recommended ATF or kerosene should be used for cleaning.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>After cleaning, the parts should be arranged in the order they were removed for efficient inspection, repair, and reassembly.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>New discs for the brakes and clutches that will be used for replacement must be soaked in ATF for at least 15 minutes before reassembly.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>All oil seal rings, clutch discs, clutch plates, rotating parts, and sliding surfaces should be coated with ATF prior to reassembly.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>All old gaskets and rubber O-rings must be replaced.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Do not apply adhesive cement to gaskets or similar parts.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Make sure that the ends of the snap rings are not aligned with any cutouts. Also make sure that snap rings are correctly installed into the grooves.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>If a worn bushing is to be replaced, the sub-assembly containing the bushing must also be replaced.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Check the thrust bearings and races for wear or damage. Replace if necessary.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Use petroleum jelly to keep parts in place.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>When working with FIPG material, perform the following:</ptxt>
<ptxt>Using a razor blade and gasket scraper, remove all old FIPG material from the gasket surface.</ptxt>
<ptxt>Clean all components thoroughly to remove all foreign matter.</ptxt>
<ptxt>Clean both sealing surfaces with a non-residue solvent.</ptxt>
<ptxt>Apply FIPG material in a continuous line approximately 2 to 3 mm (0.0787 to 0.118 in.) in diameter on the sealing surface.</ptxt>
<ptxt>Reassemble parts within 10 minutes of applying FIPG material. Failing to do so will require the FIPG material to be removed and reapplied.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten3>
</content5>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>