<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="RM21Q3EV">
<servcat id="33">
<name>TRANSMISSION</name>
<section id="1000Q_S000E" variety="S000E">
<name>A45DE AUTOMATIC TRANSMISSION</name>
<ttl id="1000Q_S000E_7A7ZD_T003R" variety="T003R">
<name>TORQUE CONVERTER CLUTCH AND DRIVE PLATE</name>
<para id="RM0000010NN01QX" category="G" type-id="3001K" name-id="AT44X-01" from="201202">
<name>INSPECTION</name>
<subpara id="RM0000010NN01QX_01" type-id="01" category="01">
<s-1 id="RM0000010NN01QX_01_0001" proc-id="RM21Q0EV__00000ZY00000">
<ptxt>INSPECT TORQUE CONVERTER CLUTCH ASSEMBLY</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="D029376E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<s2>
<ptxt>Inspect the 1-way clutch.</ptxt>
<s3>
<ptxt>Install SST to the inner race of the 1-way clutch.</ptxt>
<sst>
<sstitem>
<s-number>09350-32014</s-number>
<s-subnumber>09351-32010</s-subnumber>
</sstitem>
</sst>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Set SST so that it fits in the notch of the converter hub and in the outer race of the 1-way clutch.</ptxt>
<sst>
<sstitem>
<s-number>09350-32014</s-number>
<s-subnumber>09351-32020</s-subnumber>
</sstitem>
</sst>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>With the torque converter standing on its side, check that the clutch locks when SST is turned counterclockwise and rotates freely and smoothly when SST is turned clockwise.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="D029377E02" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<ptxt>If the results are not as specified, clean the converter and recheck the 1-way clutch.</ptxt>
<ptxt>If the results still are not as specified even after cleaning the converter, replace the converter.</ptxt>
</s3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Determine the condition of the torque converter clutch.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="D025367E04" width="2.775699831in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
<s3>
<ptxt>Check that the following conditions are met:</ptxt>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>During the stall test or when the shift lever is on N, metallic sounds are not emitted from the torque converter clutch.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>The 1-way clutch turns in one direction and locks in the other direction.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>The amount of powder in the ATF is not greater than the sample shown in the illustration.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<ptxt>If the results are not as specified, replace the torque converter clutch assembly.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<ptxt>The sample illustration shows approximately 0.25 liters (0.26 US qts, 0.22 Imp. qts) of the ATF taken from a removed torque converter clutch.</ptxt>
</atten4>
</s3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Replace the ATF in the torque converter clutch.</ptxt>
<s3>
<ptxt>If the ATF is discolored and/or has a foul odor, stir the ATF in the torque converter clutch thoroughly and drain the ATF with the torque converter facing up.</ptxt>
</s3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Clean and check the oil cooler and oil pipe line.</ptxt>
<s3>
<ptxt>If the torque converter clutch is inspected or the ATF is replaced, clean the oil cooler and oil pipe line.</ptxt>
<atten4>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Apply 196 kPa (2 kgf/cm<sup>2</sup>, 28 psi) of compressed air to the inlet hose.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>If a large amount of powder is found in the ATF, add new ATF using a bucket pump and clean the oil cooler and oil pipe line again.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</atten4>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>If the ATF is cloudy, inspect the oil cooler (radiator).</ptxt>
</s3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>Prevent deformation of the torque converter clutch and damage to the oil pump gear.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="D025368E05" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<s3>
<ptxt>When any marks due to interference are found on the end of a bolt for the torque converter clutch and on the bottom of the bolt hole, replace the bolt and torque converter clutch.</ptxt>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>Make sure all of the bolts are the same length.</ptxt>
</s3>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
<s-1 id="RM0000010NN01QX_01_0002" proc-id="RM21Q0EV__00000ZZ00000">
<ptxt>INSPECT DRIVE PLATE AND RING GEAR</ptxt>
<content1 releasenbr="1">
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="C191483E01" width="2.775699831in" height="1.771723296in"/>
</figure>
<s2>
<ptxt>Set up a dial indicator and measure the runout of the 6 portions around the torque converter fitting surfaces.</ptxt>
<spec>
<title>Maximum runout</title>
<specitem>
<ptxt>0.30 mm (0.0118 in.)</ptxt>
</specitem>
</spec>
<ptxt>If the runout is more than the maximum or if the ring gear is damaged, replace the drive plate (See page <xref label="Seep01" href="RM000000YMQ01LX"/>).</ptxt>
<torque>
<torqueitem>
<t-value1>74</t-value1>
<t-value2>755</t-value2>
<t-value4>55</t-value4>
</torqueitem>
</torque>
</s2>
</content1>
</s-1>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>