<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="NM21Q3EV">
<servcat id="58">
<name>Vehicle Interior</name>
<section id="12056_S000W" variety="S000W">
<name>SUPPLEMENTAL RESTRAINT SYSTEMS</name>
<ttl id="12056_S000W_7AI9F_T000N" variety="T000N">
<name>AIRBAG SYSTEM</name>
<para id="RM000004RTP005X" category="F" type-id="8048W" name-id="RSCH5-06" from="201403">
<name>GENERAL</name>
<subpara id="RM000004RTP005X_z0" proc-id="NM21Q0EV__000001Q00001">
<content5 releasenbr="1">
<step1>
<ptxt>OUTLINE</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>The Supplemental Restraint System (SRS) driver and front passenger airbags are used as supplements to the seat belts to help to reduce the shocks to the head and chest of the driver or front passenger in the event of a frontal collision.</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="Y112476E01" width="7.106578999in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
<table pgwide="1">
<title>Text in Illustration</title>
<tgroup cols="4">
<colspec colname="COL1" colwidth="0.71in"/>
<colspec colname="COL2" colwidth="2.83in"/>
<colspec colname="COL3" colwidth="0.71in"/>
<colspec colname="COL4" colwidth="2.83in"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>*1</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle">
<ptxt>SRS Driver Airbag</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle" align="center">
<ptxt>*2</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry valign="middle">
<ptxt>SRS Front Passenger Airbag</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>PRECAUTION</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Event Data Recorder</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>The vehicle has computers that monitor and control certain aspects of the vehicle. These computers assist in driving and maintaining optimal vehicle performance. Besides storing data useful for troubleshooting, there is an event data recorder (EDR) that records data in a crash or near crash event. The SRS airbag sensor assembly contains the EDR.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>In a crash or near crash event, this device may record the following information:</ptxt>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>SRS airbag deployment data</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>SRS airbag system diagnostic data</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>The information above is intended to be used for the purpose of improving vehicle safety performance. Unlike general data recorders, the EDR does not record sound data such as conversation between passengers.</ptxt>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Toyota will not disclose the data recorded in an EDR to a third party except when:</ptxt>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>An agreement from the vehicle's owner (or the leasing company for a leased vehicle) is obtained</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>In response to an official request by the police, a court of law or a grovernment agency</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Necessary, for use as a defense for Toyota in a law suit</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>However, if necessary, Toyota may:</ptxt>
<list1 type="unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>Use the data for research on Toyota vehicle safety performance</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Disclose the data to a third party for research purposes without disclosing details of the vehicle owner, and that only when deemed necessary</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Disclose summarized data cleared of vehicle identification information to a non-Toyota organization for research purposes</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</step3>
</step2>
</step1>
</content5>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>