<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tmc-service-inc>
<pub id="NM21Q3EV">
<servcat id="59">
<name>Vehicle Exterior</name>
<section id="12072_S0014" variety="S0014">
<name>EXTERIOR PANELS / TRIM</name>
<ttl id="12072_S0014_7AJWO_T000Y" variety="T000Y">
<name>BODY STRUCTURE</name>
<para id="RM000004S2G004X" category="F" type-id="8048W" name-id="ET6TA-05" from="201202" to="201403">
<name>GENERAL</name>
<subpara id="RM000004S2G004X_z0" proc-id="NM21Q0EV__000002R00000">
<content5 releasenbr="1">
<step1>
<ptxt>OUTLINE</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Lightweight and Highly Rigid Body</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>High-strength steel is used in order to achieve excellent body rigidity and a lightweight body.</ptxt>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Safety Features</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>The impact absorbing structure minimizes cabin deformation by effectively helping to absorb the impact energy in the event of a front or side collision. This provides high performance occupant protection.</ptxt>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Rust-resistant Body</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>Rust-resistant performance is enhanced by the extensive use of anti-corrosion sheet steel, as well as by an anti-corrosion treatment that includes the application of anti-rust wax and sealer to the easily corroded parts such as the edge of the door lower portion, door hinge, fuel filler lid hinge, the hemmed portions of the hood panel and each part of the deck.</ptxt>
</step3>
</step2>
<step2>
<ptxt>Low Vibration and Low Noise Body</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>Effective application of vibration damping and noise suppressant materials reduces engine, wind and road noise.</ptxt>
</step3>
</step2>
</step1>
<step1>
<ptxt>MAIN FEATURES</ptxt>
<step2>
<ptxt>Exterior Design</ptxt>
<step3>
<ptxt>Front View</ptxt>
<list1 type="ordered">
<item>
<ptxt>A vertical flow is used as a basis for the front design. In the center portion, an area from the hood panel to the lower end of the front bumper has been solidified into a single unit which unifies the upper and lower portions, thus expressing strength and a feeling of pushing forward.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>A trapezoidal lower grille is used for the front bumper, thus producing an aggressive feel.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>Together with an outward-protruding front turn signal light, the entire headlight assembly has been given a sharp design, thus expressing a strong image.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="V101431E01" width="7.106578999in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Rear View</ptxt>
<list1 type="ordered">
<item>
<ptxt>A back door outside garnish with a large, sharp design is used. As a result, a modern feel has been expressed for the vehicle class.</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>In the rear combination light assembly, solid clear lenses are used in the center of the red base for the rear turn signal light and back-up light portion, thus achieving a design with a high-class feel.</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="V101432E01" width="7.106578999in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
<step3>
<ptxt>Side View</ptxt>
<list1 type="ordered">
<item>
<ptxt>A large outside molding is used. As a result, the surface has a sharp and modern quality when viewed from the side.*</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type="nonmark">
<item>
<ptxt>*: Models with outside molding</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
<item>
<ptxt>A mudguard is used to give a low-center-of-gravity image for the side view.*</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type="nonmark">
<item>
<ptxt>*: Models with mudguard</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname="V101433E01" width="7.106578999in" height="3.779676365in"/>
</figure>
</step3>
</step2>
</step1>
</content5>
</subpara>
</para>
</ttl>
</section>
</servcat>
</pub>
</tmc-service-inc>