<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../styles/intro/trouble.xsl" ?>
<!DOCTYPE ewd SYSTEM "../dtd/intro.dtd">
<ewd>
	<intro xml:lang="en">
		<troubleshooting>
			<step1>
				<ptxt>VOLTAGE CHECK</ptxt>
				<cont>
					<figure src="image/tr1.png"/>
					<step2>
						<ptxt>Establish conditions in which voltage is present at the check point.</ptxt>
						<example>
							<deflist>
								<l-item>
									<label>[A]</label>
									<desc>Ignition SW on</desc>
								</l-item>
								<l-item>
									<label>[B]</label>
									<desc>Ignition SW and SW 1 on</desc>
								</l-item>
								<l-item>
									<label>[C]</label>
									<desc>Ignition SW, SW 1 and Relay on (SW 2 off)</desc>
								</l-item>
							</deflist>
						</example>
					</step2>
					<step2>
						<ptxt>Using a voltmeter, connect the negative lead to a good ground point or negative battery terminal,
								and the positive lead to the connector or component terminal.</ptxt>
						<ptxt>This check can be done with a test light instead of a voltmeter. </ptxt>
					</step2>
				</cont>
			</step1>
			<step1>
				<ptxt>CONTINUITY AND RESISTANCE CHECK</ptxt>
				<cont>
					<figure src="image/tr2.png"/>
					<step2>
						<ptxt>Disconnect the battery terminal or wire so there is no voltage between the check points.</ptxt>
					</step2>
					<step2>
						<ptxt>Contact the two leads of an ohmmeter to each of the check points.</ptxt>
						<figure src="image/tr2_2.png"/>
						<norm>
							<ptxt>If the circuit has diodes, reverse the two leads and check again.</ptxt>
							<ptxt>When contacting the negative lead to the diode positive side and the positive lead to the negative side,
									there should be continuity.</ptxt>
							<ptxt>When contacting the two leads in reverse, there should be no continuity.</ptxt>
						</norm>
					</step2>
					<figure src="image/tr2_3.png"/>
					<step2>
						<ptxt>Use a volt/ohmmeter with high impedance (10 kΩ/V minimum) for troubleshooting of the electrical circuit.</ptxt>
					</step2>
				</cont>
			</step1>
			<step1>
				<ptxt>FINDING A SHORT CIRCUIT</ptxt>
					<cont>
					<figure src="image/tr3.png"/>
					<step2>
						<ptxt>Remove the blown fuse and disconnect all loads of the fuse.</ptxt>
					</step2>
					<step2>
						<ptxt>Connect a test light in place of the fuse.</ptxt>
					</step2>
					<step2>
						<ptxt>Establish conditions in which the test light comes on.</ptxt>
						<example>
							<deflist>
								<l-item>
									<label>[A]</label>
									<desc>Ignition SW on</desc>
								</l-item>
								<l-item>
									<label>[B]</label>
									<desc>Ignition SW and SW 1 on</desc>
								</l-item>
								<l-item>
									<label>[C]</label>
									<desc>Ignition SW, SW 1 and Relay on (Connect the Relay) and SW 2 off (or Disconnect SW 2)</desc>
								</l-item>
							</deflist>
						</example>
					</step2>
					<step2>
						<ptxt>Disconnect and reconnect the connectors while watching the test light.</ptxt>
						<ptxt>The short lies between the connector where the test light stays lit and the connector where the light goes out. </ptxt>
					</step2>
					<step2>
						<ptxt>Find the exact location of the short by lightly shaking the problem wire along the body.</ptxt>
					</step2>
					<caution>
						<step-n2>
							<ptxt>Do not open the cover or the case of the ECU unless absolutely necessary.
								(If the IC terminals are touched, the IC may be destroyed by static electricity.)</ptxt>
						</step-n2>
						<step-n2>
							<ptxt>When replacing the internal mechanism (ECU part) of the digital meter,
									be careful that no part of your body or clothing comes in contact with the terminals of leads from the IC, etc.
									of the replacement part (spare part).</ptxt>
						</step-n2>
					</caution>
				</cont>
			</step1>
			<step1>
				<ptxt>DISCONNECTION OF MALE AND FEMALE CONNECTORS</ptxt>
				<cont>
					<norm>
						<ptxt>To pull apart the connectors, pull on the connector itself, not the wire harness.</ptxt>
					</norm>
					<hint>
						<ptxt>Check to see what kind of connector you are disconnecting before pulling apart.</ptxt>
					</hint>
					<figure src="image/tr4.png"/>
				</cont>
			</step1>
			<step1>
				<ptxt>HOW TO REPLACE TERMINAL</ptxt>
				<ptxt>(with terminal retainer or secondary locking device)</ptxt>
				<cont>
					<figure src="image/tr5.png"/>
					<step2>
						<ptxt>PREPARE THE SPECIAL TOOL</ptxt>
						<hint>
							<ptxt>To remove the terminal from the connector, please construct and use the special tool or like object shown on the left.</ptxt>
						</hint>
					</step2>
					<step2>
						<ptxt>DISCONNECT CONNECTOR</ptxt>
					</step2>
					<figure src="image/tr5_2.png"/>
					<step2>
						<ptxt> DISENGAGE THE SECONDARY LOCKING DEVICE OR TERMINAL RETAINER.</ptxt>
						<step3>
							<ptxt>Locking device must be disengaged before the terminal locking clip can be released and the terminal removed from the connector.</ptxt>
						</step3>
						<step3>
							<ptxt>Use a special tool or the terminal pick to unlock the secondary locking device or terminal retainer.</ptxt>
						</step3>
						<notice>
							<ptxt>Do not remove the terminal retainer from connector body.</ptxt>
						</notice>
						<figure src="image/tr5_3.png"/>
						<norm>
							<ptxt>[A] For Non-Waterproof Type Connector</ptxt>
						</norm>
						<hint>
							<ptxt>The needle insertion position varies according to the connector's shape (number of terminals etc.), so check the position before inserting it.</ptxt>
						</hint>
						<case no="1">
							<ptxt>Raise the terminal retainer up to the temporary lock position.</ptxt>
						</case>
						<figure src="image/tr5_4.png"/>
						<case no="2">
							<ptxt>Open the secondary locking device.</ptxt>
						</case>
						<figure src="image/tr5_5.png"/>
						<figure src="image/tr5_6.png"/>
						<norm>
							<ptxt>[B] For Waterproof Type Connector </ptxt>
						</norm>
						<hint>
							<ptxt>Terminal retainer color is different according to connector body.</ptxt>
						</hint>
						<example>
							<table frame="none">
								<tbody>
									<row>
										<entry><ptxt><uline>Terminal Retainer</uline></ptxt></entry>
										<entry><ptxt> : </ptxt></entry>
										<entry><ptxt><uline>Connector Body</uline></ptxt></entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry><ptxt>Black or White</ptxt></entry>
										<entry><ptxt> : </ptxt></entry>
										<entry><ptxt>Gray</ptxt></entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry><ptxt>Black or White</ptxt></entry>
										<entry><ptxt> : </ptxt></entry>
										<entry><ptxt>Dark Gray</ptxt></entry>
									</row>
									<row>
										<entry><ptxt>Gray or White</ptxt></entry>
										<entry><ptxt> : </ptxt></entry>
										<entry><ptxt>Black</ptxt></entry>
									</row>
								</tbody>
							</table>
						</example>
						<figure src="image/tr5_7.png"/>
						<case no="1">
							<ptxt>Type where terminal retainer is pulled up to the temporary lock position (Pull Type).</ptxt>
							<ptxt>Insert the special tool into the terminal retainer access hole (<figchar src="image/upmark.png" height="17" width="15" align="ABSBOTTOM"/>Mark)
								and pull the terminal retainer up to the temporary lock position.</ptxt>
						</case>
						<hint>
							<ptxt>The needle insertion position varies according to the connector's shape (Number of terminals etc.), so check the position before inserting it.</ptxt>
						</hint>
						<figure src="image/tr5_8.png"/>
						<case no="2">
							<ptxt>Type which cannot be pulled as far as Power Lock insert the tool straight into the access hole of terminal retainer as shown.</ptxt>
						</case>
						<figure src="image/tr5_9.png"/>
						<norm>
							<ptxt>Push the terminal retainer down to the temporary lock position.</ptxt>
						</norm>
						<figure src="image/tr5_10.png"/>
						<step3>
							<ptxt>Release the locking lug from terminal and pull the terminal out from rear.</ptxt>
						</step3>
					</step2>
					<figure src="image/tr5_11.png"/>
					<step2>
						<ptxt>INSTALL TERMINAL TO CONNECTOR</ptxt>
						<step3>
							<ptxt>Insert the terminal.</ptxt>
						</step3>
						<hint>
							<step-n4>
								<ptxt>Make sure the terminal is positioned correctly.</ptxt>
							</step-n4>
							<step-n4>
								<ptxt>Insert the terminal until the locking lug locks firmly.</ptxt>
							</step-n4>
							<step-n4>
								<ptxt>Insert the terminal with terminal retainer in the temporary lock position. </ptxt>
							</step-n4>
						</hint>
						<figure src="image/tr5_12.png"/>
						<step3>
							<ptxt>Push the secondary locking device or terminal retainer in to the full lock position.</ptxt>
						</step3>
					</step2>
					<step2>
						<ptxt>CONNECT CONNECTOR</ptxt>
					</step2>
				</cont>
			</step1>
		</troubleshooting>
	</intro>
</ewd>
